MONY SARY

Burbank, CA

Phone: (562) 607-9358 | Email: sary.mony@gmail.com Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mony-sary-08980b1aa/

GitHub: https://github.com/monysary
Portfolio: www.monysary.com

SUMMARY

Web Developer with skills in frontend and backend, pursuing a position in web/software development. Leveraging 6 years of experience working in biotech and clinical labs. Skills in R&D, project management, team management, and operations. Known for calm demeanor with ability to independently and quickly learn new concepts, while being proactive and maintaining deadlines.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap CSS, Tailwind CSS, Handlebars.js,

React.js, Material UI

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, APIs, Jest, Bcrypt, Socket.io

Database: MySQL, Sequelize.js, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, GraphQL, Apollo GraphQL

PROJECTS

Name: Pet Pals

GitHub: https://github.com/BryantTrinh/Pet-Pals-A-Social-Media-App-for-Pets

Link: https://hidden-headland-00556.herokuapp.com/

- Description: Social media platform for pet owners to connect and chat with each other about their pets and schedule play dates!
- Responsibilities: Frontend coding of home, feed, and chatbox components.
 Backend coding of instant messaging feature with messages saving into database.
- Tools: ReactJS, Material UI, Node.js, Apollo Server, MongoDB, GraphQL, Socket.io

Name: Bits Please Chat

GitHub: https://github.com/monysary/Bits-Please-Chat

Link: https://damp-river-11459.herokuapp.com/

- Description: An online instant messaging app where users communicate using only emojis!
- Responsibilities: Frontend coding of user interface. Backend coding of instant messaging feature, and database setup for creating user information and logging in.
- Tools: Handlebars.js, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Socket.io

Name: The Weather Dashboard

GitHub: https://github.com/monysary/Weather-Dashboard/ **Link:** https://github.com/monysary/Weather-Dashboard/

- Description: A weather app that allows users to search for current and future weather forecasts of cities, as well as save and delete the searches!
- Responsibilities: Frontend coding of user interface. Setting up API connection with public weather API and saving searches into localstorage.
- Tools: HTML, Bootstrap, Javascript, Third Party API

EXPERIENCE

Pangea Laboratory - Tustin, CA

2020 - Present

Independent Contracting Consultant - Oct 2022 to Present

- Review laboratory documents pertaining to operation, quality assurance, and assay development while maintaining compliance with regulatory standards.
- Providing consultation for DNA sequencing tests.

Laboratory Manager - Jul 2020 to Oct 2022

- Managed two separate teams concurrently, all consisting of a total of 8 technicians, 2 Clinical Laboratory Scientists, and 1 Associate Scientist.
- Initiated and led team meetings to improve laboratory operation and quality to meet regulatory standards.
- Independently researched new technology, then purchased and deployed said technology for use in the laboratory.
- Created documentation, using regulatory approved scheme, for laboratory operations
- Wrote code for methods used by automated liquid handling robots.
- In charge of implementing a new DNA sequencing test for use on patient samples while adhering to regulatory standards.
- Prepared and helped lead laboratory inspection from the College of American Pathologist.
- Worked in a team of 10 to build an entire COVID-19 testing department.

Zymo Research Corp - Irvine, CA

2018 - 2020

Senior Research Associate - Jan 2020 to Jul 2020

- Trained and managed 2 lab associates to perform a DNA sequencing assay.
- Created a small scale Laboratory Information Management System using Excel and Macros for the sequencing assay.
- Troubleshooted issues regarding the sequencing assay.

Research Associate - Jun 2018 to Jan 2020

- Maintained communication with scientists and researchers interested in performing DNA sequencing.
- Performed research and development on new reagents for operations, and deployed its use in production.
- Sequenced 1000+ DNA samples with very minimal mistakes.

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate: University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA Oct 2022 - Feb 2023

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap CSS, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Biological Sciences, B.S: University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA 2012 - 2016